MOHAMMAD HASYIM TAUFIK



GEOPHYSICIST

(+62)81517015210 - hatsyim@gmail.com - www.linkedin.com/in/hatsyim

Graduated with geophysical engineering major, I possess great enthusiasm in learning new things and overcoming obstacle related to it. On a daily basis, I am well-known as a guy who is willing to learn new things, persistence, highly empathetic with his surroundings, and a whole-hearted listener. Despite all of the awards below, actually my biggest achievement so far has been overcoming my own biggest internal enemy-obesity.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Geophysical Engineering (BSc) Bandung Institute of Technology (2015-2019)

Graduated with honors (cum laude) in July 2019, was amongst the top 1% (best graduate) of the undergraduate geophysical engineering degree for batch 2015 having the highest overall GPA; 3.78/4.00 in eight semesters.

Completed a Bachelor's thesis about near-surface geophysical data analysis to improve paleoclimate identification, entitled, "Integrated Prediction Error Filter Analysis Application on Lake Towuti."

The core and elective modules of this ASIIN-certified degree are; Wave in Geophysics, Computing in Geophysics, Physical Geology, Sedimentology and Stratigraphy, Seismology, Geostatistics, General Geophysics, Applied Environmental Geophysics, Seismic Inversion, Seismic Stratigraphy Analysis, Seismic Processing and Acquisition, Rock Physics, Geomathematics, Reservoir Geomechanics, Gravity and Magnetics, Potential Theorem, Geopressure, Well Log Analysis, Structural Geology, Exploration Geophysics, and Vulcanology and Geothermal Exploration.

Experience

Geophysicist: PT. Pertamina Hulu Kalimantan Timur, Jul 2019 – present

Currently involved in the regional joint study along the Makassar Strait. Under the name of Lembaga Penelitian dan Pengabdian Kepada Masyarakat (LPPM) ITB. The geophysical aims of this regional study are: generating well-seismic tie process, seismic data quality assessment, depth-time conversion process, and generating 3D velocity model to build 3D pore pressure cube.

Seismic Processing Lab Assistant: Bandung Institute of Technology, Jan 2019 – May 2019

Constructing a guideline in seismic data processing using ProMAX® software. Mentoring and grading the learning process of the course.

Seismology Lab Assistant: Bandung Institute of Technology, Aug 2018 – May 2019

Involved in guiding students (underclassmen) about basic theories of seismology. Mentoring and grading the learning process of the course.

Seismic Refraction Lab Assistant: Bandung Institute of Technology, Aug 2018 – Dec 2018

Guiding student (underclassmen) on fundamentals of seismic refraction. Demonstrating guidelines in processing seismic data using Seismic Unix software.

Student Intern: PetroChina International, Jun 2018 – Aug 2018

Appointed as geophysicist on the development section. Responsibilities and tasks are: analyzing elastic properties of reservoir rocks through rock physics analysis, seismic quantitative interpretation, generating well-seismic tie process, and enhancing rock properties distribution map through multi-attribute analysis.

Instrumentation in Geophysics Lab Assistant: Bandung Institute of Technology, Jan 2018 – May 2018

Guiding student (underclassmen) on fundamentals of instrumentations on geophysical engineering. Demonstrating guidelines in processing seismic data using Arduino® software.

Computational Geophysics Lab Assistant: Bandung Institute of Technology, Jan 2018 – May 2018

Constructing a guideline about the course's basic concepts using Scilab® software. Mentoring and grading the learning process of the course.

Electrical Analysis of Geophysics Lab Assistant: Bandung Institute of Technology, Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Involved in guiding students (underclassmen) about fundamental analysis of electrical system in geophysics. Mentoring and grading the learning process of the course.

Voluntary

Head of Academic Division: HIMA-TG 'TERRA' ITB, 2018 - 2019

Together with my team, we played roles in improving overall academic status of geophysical engineering student. Throughout this period of time I learned something unique as a geoscience enthusiast – humans are more complex to learn yet more fascinating than rocks. I achieved the highest overall satisfactory score among the boards of organization (BPH HIMA-TG 'TERRA' ITB 2018/2019).

Award

Best Geoscience Student Paper Presenter: The 43rd Indonesian Petroleum Association, Sep 2019

Best Thesis Defense Presentation: Geophysical Engineering Program, Bandung Institute of Technology, Jul 2019

Ganesha Prize Awardee: Bandung Institute of Technology, Jul 2019

Dean's List Awardee: Bandung Institute of Technology, 2015-2019 (Eight consecutive semesters)

First Winner of National Student Paper Competition: University of Indonesia, Feb 2019

First Winner of National Student Geoquiz Competition: Bandung Institute of Technology, Nov 2018

Finalist of International Student Paper Competition: Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, Nov 2018

First Winner of National Student Paper Competition: Trisakti University, Oct 2018

Second Winner of National Student Paper Competition: Sumatera Institute of Technology, Sep 2018

Publication

Quantitative Interpretation: A Novel Approach Using Spectral Trend Attribute Analysis and Iterative Wiener Filter in Characterizing Carbonate Reservoir on West Java Basin, Proceedings of the 43rd (International) Indonesian Petroleum Association Convention and Exhibition, Sep 2019.

Software and Skill

Writing, reading (from fiction to psychology, philosophy, and autobiography), running, football, and serving coffee (from beans to ready to sip).